<speak>
  <p>
    <s>I want to tell you a secret.</s>
    <s><emphasis level="moderate">I was scared of English grammar.</emphasis></s>
    <s>Yes... <break time="500ms"/> very scared.</s>
    <s>Tenses, prepositions, articles – I didn’t understand them.</s>
    <s>I looked at grammar books... <break time="500ms"/> and felt sleepy.</s>
    <s>Sometimes I felt <emphasis level="reduced">stupid</emphasis>.</s>
    <s>I thought, <break time="300ms"/> “Maybe I cannot learn English.”</s>
</speak>
    <s>I even thought, <break time="300ms"/> “Maybe English is not for me.”</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>But one day... <break time="500ms"/> something small changed everything.</s>
    <s>From that day, <emphasis level="moderate">grammar was not my enemy.</emphasis></s>
    <s>Grammar became my <emphasis level="strong">friend</emphasis>.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>Today, I will tell you my story.</s>
    <s>And remember: <break time="300ms"/> If I can do it... <break time="300ms"/> <emphasis level="strong">you can do it too.</emphasis></s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>Let’s go together on this journey.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>I remember my school days.</s>
    <s>My English teacher always said, <break time="300ms"/> “Learn the rules. Learn the grammar.”</s>
    <s>But grammar rules were very hard.</s>
    <s>Past perfect... future continuous... so many names!</s>
    <s>I tried to remember everything for the test.</s>
    <s>But the next day, <break time="300ms"/> I forgot.</s>
    <s>I felt bad. I felt like I failed.</s>
    <s>Sometimes I didn’t even try.</s>
    <s>I thought grammar was only for <emphasis level="moderate">smart people.</emphasis></s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>But deep inside, I still wanted to learn.</s>
    <s>I wanted to speak English. <break time="300ms"/> I just didn’t know how.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>One day, something happened.</s>
    <s>I went to the library. I wanted a storybook.</s>
    <s>But I saw a man. He was reading a grammar book. <break time="300ms"/> And he was <emphasis level="moderate">smiling!</emphasis></s>
    <s>I asked him, “Do you like grammar?”</s>
    <s>He said, “Yes. I play with grammar.”</s>
    <s>“Play?” I asked.</s>
    <s>“Yes,” he said. “I use stories. I use fun examples. I don’t just study the rules.”</s>
    <s><emphasis level="moderate">This gave me hope.</emphasis></s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>That night, I went home.</s>
    <s>I opened my grammar books. <break time="300ms"/> Then I closed them. I smiled.</s>
    <s>I took a notebook. I wrote: “Day One – Present Simple Tense.”</s>
    <s>I didn’t study 10 pages. I wrote 5 simple sentences:</s>
    <s>I wake up. I brush my teeth. I eat breakfast. I go to work. I sleep at 10 p.m.</s>
    <s><emphasis level="reduced">That’s it.</emphasis> <break time="300ms"/> It felt easy.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>Next day: Day Two – Past Simple.</s>
    <s>I woke up. I brushed my teeth. I ate breakfast. I went to work. I slept at 10 p.m.</s>
    <s><emphasis level="moderate">Grammar started to make sense.</emphasis></s>
    <s>It was my life. <break time="300ms"/> My words.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>I started talking to myself in English.</s>
    <s>Yes, it sounds funny. <break time="300ms"/> But it helped me.</s>
    <s>I said, “What did I do today?”</s>
    <s>I answered: I went to the market. I bought apples. I cooked lunch. I watched cartoons.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>I used subtitles. I paused the video. I repeated the sentences.</s>
    <s>I copied the way they spoke.</s>
    <s>I wrote small stories, like:</s>
    <s>“Yesterday, I visited my grandma. She gave me sweets. We drank tea. We talked about old times.”</s>
    <s>And when I made mistakes, I smiled.</s>
    <s>Because mistakes helped me. <break time="300ms"/> Each mistake was a small teacher.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>I didn’t study 10 hours. I didn’t go to expensive classes.</s>
    <s>I just made one small rule: <break time="300ms"/> <emphasis level="moderate">Learn one small thing every day.</emphasis></s>
    <s>One grammar point. One example. One new sentence.</s>
    <s>After 3 months, grammar was easier.</s>
    <s>After 6 months, I could speak better.</s>
    <s>After 1 year... grammar was <emphasis level="moderate">simple.</emphasis></s>
    <s>It became my friend.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>Then I learned about “parts of speech.”</s>
    <s>These are the building blocks of grammar.</s>
    <s>There are 8 parts. Let me tell you:</s>

    <s>Nouns – names: teacher, book, city.</s>
    <s>Pronouns – he, she, they.</s>
    <s>Verbs – action: eat, go, sleep.</s>
    <s>Adjectives – describe nouns: red apple, tall man.</s>
    <s>Adverbs – describe verbs: walk slowly.</s>
    <s>Prepositions – show place or time: in, on, at.</s>
    <s>Conjunctions – join words: and, but, because.</s>
    <s>Interjections – show feelings: wow, oh no, hooray!</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>I didn’t try to remember all of them.</s>
    <s>I used them in funny sentences.</s>
    <s>Like: “Wow! The red dog jumped on the table and barked loudly.”</s>
    <s>That one sentence had 7 parts of speech!</s>
    <s><emphasis level="moderate">It was fun.</emphasis> Grammar became a game.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>So my friend, listen to me.</s>
    <s><emphasis level="moderate">You don’t need to be perfect.</emphasis></s>
    <s>You only need to be <emphasis level="moderate">curious.</emphasis></s>
    <s>Grammar is not just for tests. It helps you speak. Talk about your life.</s>

    <s>Use present tense: I eat rice. I go to work.</s>
    <s>Use past tense: I ate rice. I went to work.</s>
    <s>Use future tense: I will eat rice. I will go to work.</s>
    <s>That’s it. You are learning.</s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s><emphasis level="strong">Make grammar fun.</emphasis> Make grammar your friend.</s>
    <s>Don’t be afraid.</s>
    <s>Even 100 mistakes can help you.</s>
    <s>So now, when someone says, “Grammar is boring,”</s>
    <s>I smile. Because I know – grammar is not my enemy.</s>
    <s><emphasis level="strong">It is my superpower.</emphasis></s>
  </p>

  <p>
    <s>And if I, a shy and scared student, can learn…</s>
    <s>then <emphasis level="moderate">you</emphasis> can too. Yes, <emphasis level="strong">you.</emphasis></s>
    <s>Take one small step today. Then another tomorrow. And one more the next day.</s>
    <s>Keep going. Don’t stop.</s>
    <s>Your English will grow. Your grammar will become easy.</s>
    <s>One day, someone will ask you:</s>
    <s>“How did you learn grammar?”</s>
    <s>And you will say, <emphasis level="moderate">“Let me tell you a story.”</emphasis></s>
  </p>
</speak>
